Catherine, don't!
It's still warm.
And since the teacup accidentally broke...
the culprit needs to make another kill,
to ensure that I got the message.
I have your scandal.
And if you don’t drink this,
I’ll make sure it gets out.
Drink this,
because if you don't, I'll leak your videos.
Loki!
Help!
Loki, wake up! Please, wake up!
♪ Shadows ♪
♪ in the dark are crawling. ♪
♪ Keeping watch and barring your way. ♪
♪ As if the line could not be crossed. ♪
♪ To every scream and every tremor. ♪
♪ These walls remain the only witness. ♪
♪ Every noise is etched in here. ♪
♪ Like fire and ammunition for your memory. ♪
♪ Heed the warnings. ♪
♪ The threats poised to strike. ♪
♪ For this world ♪
♪ is not what you imagined. ♪
♪ Heed the warnings. ♪
♪ Open up your eyes. ♪
♪ For this world ♪
♪ is not what you imagined. ♪
♪ Heed the warnings. ♪
No. No! No!
Lorelei! No!
No.
Lorelei, wake up.
No!
Lorelei!
Don't die on me!
Wake up!
Lorelei.
No!
Is that you?
Rhea,
what are you doing here?
How…
You’re the detective here, aren’t you?
You tell me.
The real culprit
is…
Daniel Geronimo.
I know you can solve this puzzle, Loki.
So we’re going to play a drinking game.
One contains belladonna,
and the other is just regular tea.
Loki!
Loki…
This is not real.
You really never change.
You always try to logic your way through everything.
But look what happened to you.
Oh, please!
You know me better than I am.
You know me better than anyone else.
Is Lori the new me now?
No matter how many people I meet...
no one could replace you.
Do you know she’s been watching over you
ever since she brought you here at the hospital?
She was almost crying
while the doctors pumped the belladonna out of your system.
She truly cares for you.
I noticed you two seem a lot alike.
In what way?
You’re in the same situation.
You have the same attitude.
Just like you, she doesn’t trust people easily.
But now it feels like…
you’re finally comfortable with each other.
No. I don’t think so.
I’m not even sure if she wants to be friends with me.
Really?
You practically turned the Q.E.D. Club into your home on campus.
She wouldn’t be there if she had so many other friends.
I forced her to join the club.
I'm not sure if she enjoys being a member.
She doesn’t look like she’s being forced.
She could always skip club activities or the cases.
But, look, she's always present.
Fair point.
What does she mean to you?
Is she just a club member, or another puzzle you need to solve?
Why are we even talking about her?
You really don’t get it, do you?
Get what?
Just tell me already.
You know it already. You’re just denying it.
Does it really have to come from me?
How many months has it been, Loki?
Six? Seven?
Even now, you still haven’t moved on from M.
You keep chasing him to the point that it has become your obsession.
I’m doing this for you, Rhea.
To give you justice.
Is it really for me?
Okay, fine. I understand you.
I know where you’re coming from.
But where has chasing him gotten you?
You’re putting yourself in danger.
I just want to make it up to you.
You’re dead
because…
because you’re friends with me.
So why did you recruit Lori in the first place?
The Q.E.D. Club will be dissolved if there are no other members left.
We both know that’s not true.
Just admit it already.
You need someone to talk to too, Loki.
You’re lonely.
And it’s okay for you to make a new friend.
You can’t keep depending on me when I’m no longer in this world.
But I hope your new friends help you
move on with your life and stop chasing Moriarty.
I can’t do that.
I can’t just let him be.
Once I catch him,
that’s when I can finally have some peace.
That’s when I can actually move on.
You’re still so stubborn.
That’s why you keep getting into trouble.
And the people around you too.
Listen to me, Loki.
I’m telling you,
catching Moriarty doesn’t matter because I’m no longer in this world.
There’s no point anymore.
Am I going to live?
Not anymore, right?
You’re clinging to your guilt so much, you don’t realize that it’s hurting you.
Instead of wasting your time, why not just enjoy your life?
Life is precious, Loki.
Maybe someday, I will.
I don’t know.
Looks like it’s time for me to go.
I missed our conversations.
Wait.
Where are you going?
Have you forgiven me, Rhea?
Rhea...
don't go.
I’m not the one who should forgive you, Loki.
You’ve done nothing wrong to me.
You’re the one who needs to forgive yourself.
Hey.
Wake up, sleepy head.
Loki?
Loki!
Loki.
You’re alive! You're awake!
I can’t believe that.
What’s with the overreaction?
Wait, I can’t breathe. You can let go of me now.
I might actually die.
Sorry, I’m just really happy.
But, what...
Have a seat.
Are you hungry? Thirsty? What do you need?
- Nurse! Nurse... - Okay.
Lorelei, I’m okay.
Okay.
Are you feeling dizzy?
Don’t stress yourself out.
Slowly.
Wait.
How did I get here?
Don’t tell me you carried me here from campus?
I might’ve carried you myself if I hadn’t gotten help.
Loki, wake up!
Help. Help!
Help!
- Loki's unconscious. - Loki!
Loki! Loki!
Help!
Get some help here!
Help.
Good thing Professor Morayta was near the clubroom
and called for help right away,
to bring you here at the hospital.
Prof... Professor Morayta?
Yes, my Math 100 professor.
And our client in the Stein Alberts' case.
Remember?
Yeah. I remember now.
Sorry, my mind is still in a haze.
It’s okay.
Besides, I’m really bad at remembering the names of past clients or victims.
I noticed that too.
Hey, if you see Prof, be sure to thank him, okay?
Don’t push yourself too hard yet, okay?
The doctor said to me,
there are still traces of belladonna in your system,
so you might still feel its effects.
So you need to get plenty of rest, okay?
Got it. Thank you.
By the way, what happened to my drinking buddy?
Is he alive?
Can we interrogate him?
Loki! Please stay with me, Loki.
Hang in there, Loki!
Stay with me, Loki.
Don't die on me, Loki! Come on!
Keep breathing, Loki!
Keep fighting!
Stay with me.
He didn’t make it.
The doctors suspect he was poisoned.
They’re already performing an autopsy on his body.
Is it because of belladonna?
It’s possible.
Looks like you both ingested belladonna.
But based on the initial findings,
it looks like he got the one with poison.
Later, a campus police officer will stop by
to give us a copy of the report.
Whoever gave him those tea bags...
set him up.
He wasn't told that one of the teacups was laced with poison.
Lorelei...
just a small favor, please?
Could you leave out what happened to me
when you write out your blog post about the case?
What?
Why?
I just don’t want to make things worse.
This may negatively impact our club.
No, Loki!
People should know what happened to you.
We need to be transparent to all
so they know even the Q.E.D. Club
isn’t immune to the violence and killings happening in this school.
Sorry, but I’ll have to decline your request.
Okay, Luthor. Let me handle this.
Thank you, Em.
I just have something important to attend to.
No worries.
It's okay.
Good day.
This is Emeraude Emerson.
Your Student Council President.
I know that we're all being deeply affected
by the recent deaths in our campus.
In the previous cases, it’s always been murder.
And the culprits are caught right away.
But the recent deaths,
the victims have taken their own lives.
And who is to blame for with these cases?
No one.
No one at all.
But, perhaps, they are the products of inadequate support
for the mental health of the students here in Clark U.
And maybe they don’t even realize
they're struggling psychologically and emotionally.
That’s why I ask everyone of you,
to please be kind and look out for one another.
Thank you, Student Council President, Emeraude Emerson.
Excuse me! Is it true the victims were murdered?
I read in the Q.E.D. Chronicle that they were murdered!
I don’t believe the Q.E.D. that every case has a killer!
What is it with these students? Are they killers?
What kind of school is this, a nest of criminals?
Exactly!
Those Q.E.D. people are just rage bait.
- That’s right! That’s right! - Right?
- That’s true! - They’re all just clout chasers!
Right, isn’t it?
Hey! You guys are too much!
They’re the ones helping catch the culprits!
- Stop being such haters! - That’s right!
That's right!
- They’re just clout-chasing. - Your club’s full of killers!
Your club’s full of killers!
- And you’re still defending them? - They’re the ones helping.
Everyone here is a killer.
That's true. Everyone! What?
They're the ones helping.
Where are you going?
I have to go to the restroom.
Then, I'll call the nurse.
Lorelei, I can do it.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Move!
Be careful.
Loki.
See? I told you.
You’re so stubborn.
Let me help you.
Slowly.
- Oh, no. It's locked. - Just open it.
I think I locked it.
I think, I locked it. Sorry.
Let’s just go outside.
Okay.
I got it.
Take care.
There, there's the restroom.
I'll take care of that.
Take it easy.
Take care.
Okay.
I can do it now.
- You... - You may go!
You might fall.
What if you fall or you hit your head or something?
No, why are you coming with me into the restroom?
I don’t know, I mean...
maybe you might need my assistance?
Assistance?
Really?
Eww! Loki!
You know what,
I’ll stay here outside.
You good?
Yeah.
Did you wash your hands?
Duh!
I had to make sure.
It's common sense.
My hand.
Just take it slow.
Professor Morayta!
Good afternoon!
Good thing you’re awake. How are you feeling?
Terrible, sir.
I feel like I have a hole in my stomach.
But thanks for bringing me here to the hospital.
Lorelei mentioned it earlier.
Good thing you got here in time.
Lorelei was so worried about you.
She must’ve prayed to every saint.
Just to make sure you’re safe from danger.
Come on, prof.
Really?
My subconscious said that you’re also crying.
Why would I cry over you?
We’re not even friends, right?
And maybe something just got in my eye.
Maybe it’s just a cold.
You know, you two look good together.
- What is it, sir? - What?
I’ve said that to a lot of people,
and they always end up together.
Who knows? Maybe you two are meant to be.
That would make me your matchmaker.
- Nothing like that, sir! - Impossible!
Okay, if you say so.
Anyway, take care, guys.
Loki. Especially you, Lorelei.
Who ever did this you has the intention of hurting you.
Remember that, so be careful.
Alright, I have to go.
I still need to visit my doctor friend here.
Get well soon, Loki.
Thank you, sir.
He seems and sounds so concerned about us.
We only helped him with a case once.
Wait,
are you suspecting the professor?
A bit.
Why though?
He’s the one who helped get you to the hospital.
Come on, Loki.
Professor Morayta!
-His name makes me curious.
It gives me an uncanny feeling.
Jim?
What’s so suspicious about that?
Did it remind you of someone?
In some English countries,
Jim is a nickname for James.
So what if Sir’s real name is James?
Haven’t I told you, Lorelei?
Professor Moriarty’s first name is James.
Think about it.
“Morayta” is the Filipino version of “Moriarty.”
James Moriarty, Jim Morayta.
Doesn’t that seem a little bit suspicious to you?
Is there a problem?
Nothing, sir.
There are just some small discussions going on in the Memorial Hall.
But some people are demanding accountability from the school.
Make sure there’s security stationed around the area.
I cannot afford another chaotic incident in this school.
Yes, sir.
Chief Estrada has already dispatched some police to the area.
Thank you. You may go.
Everything is under control.
Trolls have already been hired against the Q.E.D. Club.
Come in!
Oh, good eve...
Are you okay, officer?
Sorry, Chief Estrada isn’t here right now.
He’s investigating another case.
Oh, this is Daniel Geronimo’s autopsy report.
Sorry.
I just noticed...
you seem pretty young.
It’s like we’re the same age.
Yeah, you look like you just came out of the academy.
Oh, yeah.
I’m still a rookie officer with the campus police, so…
Sorry, of course I remember you.
We’ve just been a little preoccupied solving cases,
so we haven’t really gotten to talk to you much.
It’s okay, it’s okay.
A rookie, huh?
Is that why they’re asking you to run errands?
How many crime scenes have you worked, Officer…
Just call me Bastien. Just Bastien.
During my first month at the campus police station,
I was mostly on desk duty.
But this year, they started taking me to crime scenes,
so I’m still a little nervous.
So, that’s the…
Take a look.
Traces of Atropa belladonna and hemlock were found in the victim's system.
The ingestion of their poisons resulted in anticholinergics syndrome
and respiratory failure, respectively.
Hemlock?
Poison hemlock is one of the plants that contains toxic alkaloids.
Depending on the dosage,
symptoms can appear anywhere from 30 minutes to three hours.
As the chief medical examiner said, toxins act fast once ingested.
So…
if the victim had been taken to the hospital right away,
he might’ve still survived.
You’re lucky you didn’t get the tea bag with hemlock.
It’s not luck,
it’s instinct.
Do you mind if I sniff the scent of these teas?
Be my guest.
Both teas had the same color and scent,
so I thought of another factor to consider before choosing.
And I noticed that there’s a slight difference
between the two tea bags.
I made my choice based on their appearance.
But no matter what you say,
it was still luck.
You gambled on a 50/50 chance of getting the tea without hemlock.
You don’t even know what a dried hemlock plant looks like.
Whatever you say.
If you don’t have any more questions,
I’ll head to the police station first.
I only extended my shift a bit.
And, Loki, get well, okay?
Lori, I’ll go ahead.
- Alright, officer. - Bye, thank you!
- Sorry. - Sorry.
Loki, Lori. Thank you.
What?
Just checking if I’m still alive?
Or are you here to finish the job?
Did you seriously think that I wish for my brother’s death?
By the way, Lorelei...
on behalf of the Mendez family, thank you for taking care of him.
It’s nothing.
Anytime.
It’s my pleasure.
Did you come here to take photos of me while I’m at my most vulnerable state?
Now you’re thinking of using them to blackmail me someday,
so I can be a dog to do your bidding?
Sorry, but...
that won’t work on me.
Loki, see, I didn’t come here to fight you.
Prof Morayta told me what happened to you.
And as your older brother, I’m just here to check on you.
Your obligation as a brother.
So what, do I still owe you? Am I supposed to be touched?
You know, it’s ironic because I did warn you.
Stop looking for M.
You’ve faced M’s minions twice,
and you've seen what they’re capable of.
You never learn, huh?
Well,
the more minions we encounter,
the more pieces of information we get.
So don’t rush,
we’ll catch him eventually.
What, Lorelei? Are you…
Are you just gonna go on with his bullshit?
You knew it was gonna be dangerous.
And you’re still going to continue this?
Do you really want her to be the next Rhea?
If the club wants to handle a case,
I’ll make it happen,
because it’s my duty as a member of the club.
But if not,
I’ll just let it be and stay out of it.
That’s my position!
Let’s get this straight.
Rhea’s name does not mean death,
and it never will.
Have some respect, will you?
My apologies then.
But are you sure?
I can’t stop you from this craziness?
Not anymore.
Get out of here.
You know, I just hope I don’t end up seeing either of you in the morgue.
And if I do, you will no longer hear me saying...
I told you so.
Do you remember what John Bautista said about M
when he was interviewed by the campus police?
Which one?
He said he talks to M over the phone.
Can you describe his voice?
Just...
cold and deep.
The kind that...
The kind that sends chills down your spine when you hear it.
Luthor’s voice matches that description.
Deep, cold,
and chilling.
I noticed that too.
Did it ever cross your mind
that your brother is Moriarty?
What makes you think that way?
Loki, Luthor is the Vice President of the Student Council.
Just like you said before, he’s the one in control of this.
I assume he also has a lot of influence on campus.
He’s in the perfect position to do terrible things.
My brother may be despicable,
but he’s not a monster.
He gets what he wants through manipulation
but not murder.
Yeah, his voice is chilling,
but it doesn’t mean anything.
- But there’s a possibility... - I get where you’re coming from.
But he's not M.
Serena did not deserve to die this way.
She’s my friend. She still had so many dreams.
What I can’t accept
is that she was a strong, confident, independent woman,
and her life just ended like that.
According to the Q.E.D. Club,
someone’s orchestrating the murders at this school.
Someone needs to be held accountable for this!
Justice for Serena!
Justice for Isaac!
President Alcantara is useless!
Defend for Clark U!
Right! You guys are wrong! They are wrong!
You guys are wrong!
Campus Police, it’s chaos here. Please do something.
Stop it already. Come on.
Liar!
Do you really want her to be the next Rhea?
I just hope I don’t end up seeing either of you in the morgue.
And if I do, you will no longer hear me saying...
I told you so.
That’s pretty deep.
- Nurse Melissa. - Hi.
So you're a resident here?
Yes. How’s Loki doing?
So you heard about it.
He’s doing okay. He’s recovering now.
I understand why your sigh was so deep.
Just earlier, I heard the students were in an uproar.
Because they all have different opinions about what’s happening.
Some of them want justice.
Others are still in denial.
My God.
Sometimes, I think bad luck is really following me.
From my previous school all the way here at Clark U,
I carried it with me.
What if I just let Loki deal with the cases by himself?
Maybe then he won’t be put in danger anymore.
The thing is...
if I stay away from him,
how sure am I this will all stop?
It’s okay to think about those things.
But whatever you decide, make sure it comes from good intentions.
And stop blaming yourself.
None of what’s happening is your fault.
What happened to Loki isn’t your fault. It’s not you.
Thank you, Nurse Mel.
I really just want all of this to be over.
I just don’t know how or when.
Only time will tell.
Not everything has to be rushed.
But sometimes, maybe you need to go through it to learn something.
Be open to make mistakes, just learn from it.
Hello?
Hello, Lori!
Lori’s not here.
Can you please stop calling?
Loki?
Where’s Lori?
I don’t know.
She went outside.
If it’s not urgent,
call her later.
I really need to talk to her.
Things are getting a little chaotic at the...
Wait.
You’re in the hospital, right?
Yeah. So what?
So if you’re in the hospital,
that means Lori’s alone at the Q.E.D. Club right now?
Can she solve cases on her own?
You know, I can help her
so she won’t have to do it alone or struggle too much.
Just let me join your club already.
That’s still a no.
But why though...
He's so grumpy. He could at least...
Loki?
Oh, my God! Oh, my God, Loki!
What kind of mess did you get yourself into, huh?
This kid... Wait.
- Where’s Lori? - Hey, Tita Martha.
- You're here? - Wait.
- How are you? Do you feel anything? - No, I'm okay.
- Are you sure? Huh? - I'm fine.
Are you okay? Huh?
- You’re not feeling anything? - I'm okay.
If you’re okay, then why... Where did you come from?
Sorry, Tita. I just went out to get some air.
- Got some air? - Yeah.
You’re not supposed to leave him alone!
What is it with you two? My God!
Lori, Loki, do you know I almost had a heart attack, huh?
When I got your text.
You two are unbelievable. What's wrong with you two?
You shouldn’t be drinking whatever people offer you.
Just to be safe, why don’t you bring your own tumbler?
Aren’t those trendy with young people these days?
Why don’t you just drink from those instead?
- Tita? - What?
- Would you like something to drink? - Yes!
I can buy you something from the canteen.
Alright! Anywhere’s fine! Your call!
Can you buy me coffee?
- You can't have coffee! - You can't have coffee!
- Alright, I’ll head out first. - Hurry up! Go on!
Do you want some fruit?
- Yes, ma'am? Okay. - Hello, miss! One soda, please.
- Ma'am. - Thank you.
Paging Dr. De Vera, to the ER, please.
Dr. De Vera, to the ER.
Paging Dr. Sy, to the OR, please.
Dr. Sy, to the OR.
Paging Dr. Sanchez, please proceed to the Nurse Station.
-Dr. Sanchez, to the Nurse Station, please.
Paging Dr. Uy, please proceed to the ER. Dr. Uy, to the ER, please.
Do I know you, miss?
Did I do something wrong to you?
Sorry, sir.
Sorry, I bothered you.
I startled you.
Okay.
Sir, what song are you whistling?
Isn’t that a children’s song?
Yeah.
What was that again?
Mary Had a Little Lamb?
That’s it! Right!
I think it was a keypad tone.
I heard someone dialing.
Where did you hear that?
There, inside the CR.
Thank you, sir.
Who are you?
Lorelei!
Moriarty.
Moria...
- Moria... - Moriarty.
Over here.
It’s not safe to be out this late by yourself.
Hey.
Our normal counting system is called “base ten.”
I’m here to formally let you know
that our EIC wants to include some of your works.
- What? - I wanted to bring a case to you.
Of course! What is it?
He's such a loser.
I want you to write it in a secured drive.
Do you have a case you want to bring to us?
I do, actually. Someone’s been bothering my friend.
But it’s okay! It’s okay!
Maybe next time, when your partner gets back.